Daniel Suárez Arias

Grecia, Costa Rica· linkedin.com/in/daniel-suárez-arias/ · +506 71141625 · dani.sua.ari.ds@gmail.com

2 years of experience as a Software Developer. I managed to optimize loading times to display the products available in the online shop in Globaly, achieving a considerable improvement in customer satisfaction. I also had the opportunity to develop from scratch an ATS for 4Geeks.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

4Geeks San José, Costa Rica

Django and Angular developer

May 2023-December 2023

- I successfully developed a real-time messaging system using websockets and docker, implemented libraries such as redis **channels** and **daphne**.
- I managed to correct errors that had some queries related to pagination that needed to be optimised.
- Design a new fully refactored section to display the candidate profiles of recruiters to show their information such as studies, technical skills and general profile information.
- I also participated in the implementation of a summary parser for the automatic extraction of information from candidates' CVs for recruiters using tools such as google cloud functions as well as the OpenIA API to perform the conversions.
- I participated in the quality control of the tickets that were being worked on and I also learnt how to work on them in a management tool using agile methodologies (Scrum).

San Pedro, Costa Rica Globaly

JavaScript developer and python developer

December 2023-January 2024

- I implemented a functionality to search for specific products in different Globaly partner shops, showing the customer the product they are looking for in their nearest location.
- Optimise the time spent displaying products to customers and present them in a carousel style format with a considerable improvement over the previous design.
- I successfully implemented artificial intelligence for classification according to the type of product to be registered in the system, training the AI to differentiate between each item according to its information.

ANCTS San José, Costa Rica Enero 2024-Present

Django developer

- Successfully participate in a CRM sales system with reporting, statistical information within the system as well as the possibility to make sales within the system.
- I managed to develop custom libraries in python for handling queries to payment gateways using tools such as postman and sandbox with test cards to make sales and verify that they are performing transactions correctly.
- I also participated in all the software quality control processes to maintain the integrity of the data as well as to correctly verify its functionalities.
- I developed system information sorting functions with different parameters, according to the client's information visualisation needs.
- Design and implement the colour palette and layout of the system using design patterns as well as help with visual enhancement for the CRUD modules in some sections.
- I optimised the update of a large number of logs that were being performed one by one using signals so that each log update was parsed multiple times and thus saved a large amount of time.

EDUCACIÓN

University of Costa Rica

Bachelor's Degree in Business Informatics

Puntarenas, Costa Rica

Abril 2024

National Institute of Apprenticeship

English with customer service training

Grecia, Costa Rica
Diciembre 2018

Technical Skills

- Python
- Django
- Angular
- Javascript
- Docker
- Git
- Linux
- SQL/PL-Sql/T-SQL